

CONTACT INFORMATION

Number: (917) 847-1533

Email: 1jessicaperez@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/jessica-p-a13a20b5

Portfolio: https://jessica-perez-portfolio.netlify.app/

Github: https://github.com/JessicaPerez1

PERSONAL PROFILE

Enthusiastic Frontend web developer with recent experience working on a React/Redux app. Experience with full-stack projects as well. Strong team management, communication and quick learning skills. Organized to meet deadlines, fulfill clients' expectations and create flawless user experience. Fluent in French, English, proficient in Spanish.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- HTML / CSS (expert)
- Javascript / jQuery (expert)
- ReactJS / Redux (proficient)
- Bootstrap (expert)
- NodeJS (proficient)
- MaterialUI (prior experience)
- Express (prior experience)
- MongoDB / MySQL (prior experience)
- Devops: Project management (Trello), interface design (Figma, Miro) and version control (Git).

MORE SKILLS

- Determined
- Empathetic
- IndependantTeam Player
- Quick Learner
- Team Management
- · Good communicator
- Organized
- Like a good daily laugh @

PROJECTS

HAPPY CLOUD

- Deployed: https://bit.ly/2ZHmT0O
- Github: https://bit.ly/2Eb3w90
- MERN stack app.

TEAM PROFILE GENERATOR

- Live Demo: https://bit.ly/3my191p
- Github: https://bit.ly/2GZx7TI
- Node CLI app using Inquirer.

JESSICA PEREZ

Frontend Web Developer

RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

Frontend Web Developer/ReactJS

Cobalt, New York (remote) - Nov 2020-March 2021 **Cobalt website:** https://cobalt.co/

- Built the 'Develop Idea' section: Save user's data to the DB, enable them to retrieve/update the data any time to streamline the user experience.
- Pull in saved user data to populate "Project Details" with proper project information: allow the user to access project details for editing.
- Create a responsive sidebar and notifications for an intuitive and optimized navigation.
- Added DraftJs to all form inputs that allows the user to enter rich text.
- Ensured newly created projects' design match general website design for a harmonious UI.
- React app using Redux, hooks, form validation/control, Routes, RESTful Apis, CSS.

Operational Manager

Via Carota & Bar Pisellino, New York - Apr 2019-March 2020 2019 James Beard Best Chef NYC award winner

- Daily decision making, troubleshooting, operational and administrative tasks.
- Document systems and streamline processes for both locations.
- Interviewed, trained, developed staff conducted performance reviews to optimize productivity.
- Upheld service standards and product quality, guest interaction, cultivated relationships, planed and executed events.

US Regional Strategic Marketing Manager Consultant

LVMH, Make Up For Ever, New York - Sep 2017-Apr 2018

- Led the brand's 360 integrated marketing planning efforts against the overall brand/product calendar.
 Drove omnichannel strategy, planning and execution.
- Grew brand awareness, engagement, equity, and new client acquisition by identifying and implementing collaborations with new and existing partners - sampling and brand partnerships.
- Kicked off and executed projects by working closely with all teams. Developed assets, ensured product availability and on time delivery, budget tracking and cost of program negotiation.
- Drove post campaign analysis, shared key insights with team leaders to optimize future campaigns.

Global Business Development & Marketing

Shiseido, Nars Cosmetics, New York - Jan 2016-Aug 2017

- Connected NY HQ teams with International partners to ensure execution on all marketing aspects.
 Optimized markets' strategic decisions. Compiled and presented marketing analytics for campaign optimization.
- Developed localized product launches to achieve business goals: +54% FY 2016 in Asia, +37% in Europe, +194% in Travel Retail Asia.
- Led pricing strategy for markets' best positioning and to increase profitability.
- Owned strong partnerships with headquarter teams, International teams, and agency partners.

EDUCATION

Fullstack Web Development Bootcamp Certificate

Columbia University, New York - June-Sept 2020

A.I.C/D.U.T Advertising/ Marketing - Thesis presented to a jury of professionals

Michel de Montaigne University, Bordeaux, France - 2004-2007